So now let's talk about
the AWS Global Accelerator.
It is used to improve the global application availability
and performance using the AWS global network.
The idea is that your requests are going to be routed
through the internal network we saw from before from AWS
and this is going to allow you to optimize the route
to your application for about 60%.
So lets take an example,
We have deployed an application browser in India
and users all around the world
want to access our application.
What they will do using the Google Accelerator
is actually connect to an edge location
and the edge location will be routing the traffic
directly into India.
Well, the benefit we get out of it is that
the traffic on the public internet only happens
between America and the closest edge location
and then it leverages the private AWS network
to speed up the connection from the Edge location
to your application browser.
So this is the same for Europe
and this is the same for Australia.
On top of it, you only access your application
through two static IPs called Anycast IPs
and then using the static Anycast IP,
you will be redacted automatically
to the correct edge location.
And then the edge location, as I said,
will be sending the traffic to your application.
So there's a diagram I really liked from the website of AWS
which is showing what happens without a Global Accelerator.
So your clients to get to your application in your region
can go through a lot of hops an a lot of network
and there could be problems
and there could be latencies added to it.
But if you use the Global Accelerator
then you just connect to an Edge location of AWS
and then very quickly from the Edge location
to the region you're connecting to,
it goes through the private AWS network,
which is much faster.
Finally, I also get questions around what is the difference
between Global Accelerator and CloudFront.
So they both use the global network of AWS
and the edge locations around the world.
And they will both integrate with Sheild for DDoS protection
but CloudFront is a content delivery network
which is used to cage content at the edge such as images,
videos, and websites
and the content is served at the edge with CloudFront.
Okay.
Because it caged at the edge location.
For Global Accelerator, there is no caching.
All the requests are going to be passed on
from the edge locations
back to your application in your regions.
And so therefore what it's going to do
is that it's going to improve the performance
of these queries over a wide range of TCP or UDP
which is amazing if you have an HTTP use case
if you require a static IP address
or if you require fast deterministic
regional failover and good performance.
So remember they're very different.
CloudFront is a content delivery network,
you cage content at the edge
and Global Accelerator is to make your request go faster
and go through the internal AWS network globally.
So I'd like to show you a small tool
which allows you to do a speed comparison
for AWS Global Accelerator.
Okay.
So this is a speed comparison tool which allows you to see
if Global Accelerator makes a difference
compared to the public internet.
So let's do a test of five megabytes.
And what this is going to do is to try to upload a file
of five megabytes or download it as well, sorry,
in different regions around the world
regardless of if it's going over direct internet
or global accelerator.
And so it does it region by region
as we can see in a US-based one, Northern Virginia,
if I wanted to download a file over the internet
it was done in over 1,293 millisecond.
Whereas using Global Accelerator,
it was 23% faster because it was only 1002 milliseconds.
So this is going to make a huge difference for regions
that are far away from me.
So I'm in Europe, so Northern Virginia is far away from me,
it's across the ocean.
Oregon as well, it's on the West Coast of the US
so it's across the ocean and across the US.
So I'm getting a 31% improvement of speed,
but Ireland, which is a region that's literally next to me
as we can see, we have the same performance
over the internet or Global Accelerator
because it says next door, same for Frankfurt, Tokyo,
I'm getting better performance.
Singapore I expect also a better performance
and Sydney I expect a huge performance differential.
So let's have a look at the results in a second,
but what this shows you is that using Global Accelerator
because it goes over the private network of AWS
as fast as early on as possible,
you are going to get better performance
and this is the whole idea behind Global Accelerator.
So Singapore, yes, was 34% faster, which was great.
So 5,000 milliseconds versus 3.4 seconds.
And to finish with Sydney, I'm seeing a 53% improvement
in speed with Global Accelerator.
So this really shows you the power of Global Accelerator
when you have global applications.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.